

Solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web application using latest technology. Experience building product for Web App, Application and Organization Management System meeting highest standards for design development, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges developing solutions and building applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

### CONTACT

PHONE:

+977-9851236141

WFBSITE:

https://binodgiri.com.np

EMAIL:

info@binodgiri.com.np

# **HOBBIES**

Chess Football RPG Games Learning

# BINOD GIRI

Programmer / Web Developer

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Islington College**

13 Aug, 2015

[During college day we have worked on the project for Government of Nepal, Cyber Division.]

Columbus H.S.S

2010-2012

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Mahayogi Siddhababa Spiritual Academy [Chief Technical Person]

28 Nov, 2020 - Current

- ⇒ Analysis and support IT infrastructure throughout organization.
- ⇒ Data analysis.
- ⇒ Overview All Communication channels.
- Adintain Internal Network system and troubleshoot any related problem throughout organization.
- Communicate with different international organization for deployment and support.

# Chandragiri Education Hub [Computer Teacher]

17 April 2018 - 2020

- $\Rightarrow$  In charge to overview all students within organization.
- ⇒ Walkthrough all admission process for students.
- ⇒ Computer Teacher for Basic and Advance course

# Government of Nepal, Land and Revenue Department [Computer Operator & Technician]

17 April, 2018 - 26 Sep, 2019

- Monitored systems in operation and input commands to troubleshoot areas such as Networking and Online Land & Revenue department Portal (Kalanki Department).
- ⇒ Worked with Varieties of customers and understand needs and provide support for register property based on needs and documents submitted.
- Adintain Internal network system and troubleshoot any IT related problem within branch.
- ⇒ Was actively present during the development of new Land and revenue online system (PAM)

# SOCIAL



Binodgiri41 Id: 3551712

# Bluebell Software solutions [Sr. Web Developer]

Vizramba Computer Institute [Programming Teacher]

programming and communication.

⇒ Provide support for final year assessment.

⇒ Private tutor for engineering student in the field of

15 Dec,2015-28 Feb, 2018

17 April, 2018 - 26 Sep, 2019

- ⇒ Used programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed.
- ⇒ Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment.
- ⇒ Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Represented web team at meetings with executives and discussed project goals and milestones.
- Developed user-oriented visuals and features using front-end languages, including HTML, CSS and JavaScript, JQuery.
- Delivered user support to clients to train, educate and answer questions.
- → Maintained strict budgetary and scheduling guidelines to satisfy customers with high-quality, targeted designs.

### **TRAININGS**

### RCHE (I.T. Security Nepal)

Currently Studying.

## The Practical Way of Project Management

15 Jul - 21 Jul, 2015

### **Zend Training**

MCSE - Microsoft Certified System Engineer

**CCNA - CISCO Certified Network Associate** 

### **SKILLS**

- Communications
- Team Management
- Team Building
- Programming
- Agile workflow process
- Website Optimization
- Web Development Project